Jake Hatfield

🗣 Houston, TX 🛮 me@jake-hatfield.com 📞 +1 (979) 739-6670 🗘 github.com/jake-hatfield 🗞 jake-hatfield.com

Software Engineer (Full Stack)

Software engineer with over 3 years of holistic, full-stack experience involving designing, architecting, and programming software-as-a-service (SaaS) web apps that scale. Cross-disciplinary JavaScript engineer able to break down complex problems in order to create a minimum viable product that can be progressively improved and easily maintained.

Experience

Leadgeek Sep 2020 - Present

Founder & Chief Technology Officer

Houston, TX

- Designed and engineered a bootstrapped SaaS that provides arbitrage leads for Amazon sellers which grew to \$70K+ annual recurring revenue and 420+ users in 2022. Overhauled the subscription model and code base in Q1 2023 to a self-service, pay-as-you-go structure in order to facilitate a 250% growth in maximum revenue.
- Created from scratch 48 reusable, mobile-responsive front-end components, 30 unit and integration tests, 38 public pages, 82 RESTful APIs, 3 Cron jobs, 4 webhooks, and blog, documentation, admin, and affiliate systems.
- Reduced perceived load times by 80% for data-intensive pages by selectively prioritizing and hybridizing server and client-side API calls, resulting in a complete elimination of user reports regarding slow page speed.
- Designed and developed a one-of-a-kind feature that uses the Amazon Selling Partner API to check each user's product restrictions and routinely send an email notifying them about the new products they can arbitrage.
- Technologies: v2 TypeScript, SvelteKit, Supabase, Vitest, Playwright, D3.js, Stripe, SendGrid, Github Actions, Sentry, Vercel | v1 Web App - React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Heroku | v1 Site - Gatsby.js, GraphQL, Stripe, Netlify

Mar 2020 - Present **Freelance**

Web Developer Houston, TX

• Collaborated with a client to provide advice regarding system design and architecture that helped refine their goals for a college essay proofreading SaaS. Individually designed and engineered the full-stack web app, involving authentication, payments, user onboarding, file upload/download, email/SMS notifications, and databasing.

Apr 2018 - Mar 2020 **Kilburn Industries** Chief Operating Officer Dallas, TX

 Developed wholesale, supplier, and direct brand e-commerce relationships that resulted in revenue of \$550K+ during the 2018-2019 period, leading to placement in the top 3% of third-party Amazon sellers globally.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, React, React Native, Redux, Next.js, Gatsby.js, Svelte, SvelteKit, TailwindCSS, GraphQL, SQL, Supabase, NoSQL, Firebase, MongoDB, Mongoose, Vitest, Jest, Playwright, D3.js, Expo, Git

Projects

Doom Scheme - TypeScript, React Native, Firebase, Node.js, Express.js, OpenAl GPT-3, Cyclic Mar 2023 - Present

• Currently building a React Native app for composing and sharing rap verses. Features include a dictionary and thesaurus API, syllable counter, and GPT-3-powered completion of user input using consonance, slant rhymes, onomatopoeia, etc. Users can share their rap lyrics as well as view and like other raps shared for public discovery.

C-Meme30 - TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, Discord.js, Railway

A bot for Discord servers that joins the user's voice channel and plays a line from Star Wars preguels on command.

Education

Texas A&M University 2016 B.S. Biology College Station, TX